Hello, English learners,
and welcome back to
another episode of English
Pod, my name is Marco.
And I'm Erica.
And today, with Erica,
we are getting married.
Well, we're not getting married.
We're not, but our
actors in the podcast are.
That's right, so we've got a
lesson today about weddings.
And, you know what,
a lot of the language in
this lesson is about
weddings and marriages.
And maybe you don't
need to use this language
every day, but
learning this vocabulary
will definitely help you understand or
learn a lot more about Anglo culture.
Okay, great point, Marco.
I think now we can look
at our vocabulary preview.
vocabulary preview.
So two simple words in
this vocabulary preview.
The first one is "Groom".
"Groom".
So who is the groom?
Is the man, the man that's getting married.
Okay, and our second word is "Bried".
"Bried".
And obviously the bride is
the woman getting married.
Perfect.
Now we have our bride
and our groom, so it's
time to listen to our
dialogue the first time.
I can't believe that Anthony
is finally getting married.
Yeah, well, it's about time.
You've been living with
his parents for 40 years.
Don't be mean.
Look, here come the bride's maids.
Oh, their dresses look beautiful.
Who are those kids walking down the aisle?
That's the flower girl and the rain bear.
I'm pretty sure that they're
the groom's niece and nephew.
Oh, they look so cute.
I just hope the priest
makes it quite feel starving.
I hope the food's good at the reception.
That's all you ever think about.
Food.
Oh, I think the bride's coming now.
Oh, she looks gorgeous.
Wait, what's she doing?
Where is she going?
So great.
Does this mean that
the reception is canceled?
Oh, Markle, that's so sad.
Yeah, I know the reception is canceled now.
Markle!
We're not getting married.
Oh, well, I mean, the best part is when
you go and eat and drink at the reception.
Okay.
Well, there's some great
language in this dialogue.
And now let's look at
our language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Great.
Our first word on the language
takeaway today is it's about time.
It's about time.
So now we are going to listen to some
examples on how we use this great phrase.
Example one.
Dinner's ready.
It's about time.
I'm starving.
Example two.
Guess what?
I finally got a job.
It's about time.
Example three.
We're almost there.
Just a couple more minutes.
It's about time.
We've been driving for 12 hours.
So this phrase means finally.
Finally, at last.
We've been waiting a long time for this.
Exactly.
Okay.
So it's about time.
Great.
Let's take a look at our second word now.
Isle.
A-I-S-L-E.
It's a tricky word.
It sounds like the contraction of I will.
Yeah, but it's spelled so strangely.
Right.
We don't pronounce the S.
The S is silent.
That's true.
Isle.
So what is an Isle?
In a big room where
you have a lot of chairs.
That space in the middle that
allows people to walk through.
That's the Isle.
So the Isle is the part where you walk.
Yes.
In a big room.
With many chairs.
Okay.
So in the church.
The bride and groom walked on the Isle.
Exactly.
Great.
Let's move to our third word.
Bridesmaid.
So who are the bridesmaids?
Or maybe you should ask me that.
Yeah.
Because we don't get bridesmaids.
Okay.
So the bridesmaids are the
women who are friends of the
bride who stand next to her
when she's getting married.
Usually they're her best friends.
Right.
Okay.
So we have our bridesmaids.
Now we have our flower girl.
Flower girl.
Again.
I'll explain this one.
Please.
The flower girl is
that cute little girl who
walks down the aisle
and who throws flowers.
That's the flower girl.
And with the flower girl,
we have our ring bearer.
Ring bearer.
So the ring bearer
is the cute little boy
who walks down the
aisle carrying the rings.
Yep. Okay. So a lot of useful
vocabulary for a wedding ceremony.
That's true.
Now let's look at our last word.
Gorgeous.
Gorgeous means beautiful.
Very beautiful.
Yeah.
You know, beautiful you
can only use with a woman.
Can you use gorgeous
with a woman or with a man?
Yes.
Gorgeous is unisex.
So both men and women are gorgeous.
Right.
You can say, oh, that girl is gorgeous.
That guy is gorgeous.
Right.
Or you can say even this house is gorgeous.
Okay.
So men, women, objects.
Yes.
All right.
Well, we've learned
some really interesting
vocabulary that will help us to
understand an Anglo wedding.
So why don't we listen to
the dialogue slowed down.
I can't believe that Anthony
is finally getting married.
Yeah.
Well, it's about time.
He's been living with
his parents for 40 years.
Don't be mean.
Look, here come the bridesmaids.
Their dresses look beautiful.
Who are those kids walking down the aisle?
That's the flower girl and the ring bearer.
I'm pretty sure they're the
groom's niece and nephew.
Oh, they look so cute.
I just hope the priest makes it quick.
I'm starving.
I hope the food's good at the reception.
That's all you ever think about.
Food.
Oh, I think the brides coming now.
She looks gorgeous.
Wait.
What's she doing?
Where's she going?
Oh, great.
Does this mean that
the reception is canceled?
Now in this dialogue, we have a word
that many students often make mistakes on.
So this is a word that
causes a lot of problems.
Yes, the word marry.
Marry.
Marry, right?
So we are going to listen
now to some common
mistakes on how English
learners use this word.
Right, so these are wrong examples.
Example one.
Honey, let's marry.
Example two.
We married four years ago.
Example three.
When I marry, I want a huge wedding.
These are great examples of
mistakes students make with the word.
Marry, they're missing a word.
Let's listen to these right examples
to see what word is missing.
Example one.
Honey, let's get married.
Example two.
We got married four years ago.
Example three.
When I get married, I want a huge wedding.
Great, so we can see that when we use
the word marry, we say to get married.
Exactly right.
Get married.
To get married, right?
Okay, don't forget that.
Yes, get married.
I will get married.
We got married.
Right.
So now you know exactly
how to use this word.
We are ready to listen to our
dialogue again for a third time.
And this time it's going
to be at a normal speed.
I can't believe that Anthony
is finally getting married.
Yeah, well, it's about time.
You've been living with
his parents for 40 years.
Don't be mean.
Look, here come the bridesmaids.
Oh, their dresses look beautiful.
Who are those kids walking down the aisle?
That's the flower girl and the rain bear.
I'm pretty sure that they're
the groom's niece and nephew.
Oh, they look so cute.
I just hope the priest makes it quick.
They're starving.
I hope the food's good at the reception.
That's all you ever think about.
Food.
Oh, I think the brides coming now.
Oh, she looks gorgeous.
Wait, what's she doing?
Where is she going?
So great.
Does this mean that
the reception is canceled?
Okay.
Well, I'm going to be honest with you.
I don't know too much about marriages
because, first of all, I'm not married.
And I've never really
been to many marriages.
So, Erica, some questions for you.
Okay.
What are these bridesmaids do?
I mean, what are they about?
What are the bridesmaids do?
Yeah, what are they doing there?
Well, like I said earlier, the
bridesmaids are the friends of the brides.
But the most important
people besides the bride
and groom are the best
man and the maid of honor.
Okay.
And what do they do there in the ceremony?
Well, what they do is they
sign the marriage license.
Okay.
So they're like witnesses.
Exactly.
Okay.
So, but wait a minute.
They sign the marriage
license there in the church.
Yeah, of course.
Right inside the church.
You sign the marriage license.
Oh, that's strange
because from what I know,
in other countries, usually you will sign
the marriage license before the ceremony.
So, you get married twice.
Yeah, you have like the
civil marriage and then
you have like the church
wedding or whatever.
That's so complicated.
Well, yeah.
I mean, the church
wedding is just a ceremony.
It's not really anything official.
Oh, in Canada, it's
the official part as well.
I guess maybe you're just more efficient.
Maybe.
Well, this is a really fascinating, a
really interesting subject, isn't it?
Yeah, because there's so many countries
that have different marriage ceremonies.
I know that marriage is in
India last around seven days.
Yeah, yeah.
I want to know more about how
our users get married in their country.
Yeah.
So, please go to our
website at englishpod.
com and tell us how you
get married in your countries.
Yeah, I can't wait to hear your stories.
Yeah, it should be interesting, right?
Okay.
Well, everyone, thanks for listening.
And until next time, goodbye.
Bye.